Hanna Alemu

Software Developer

Seattle, WA 206.573.0966

hanna9alemu@gmail.com

https://hannaaa.com/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/hannaalemu/

https://github.com/hannaalemu

Profile

FullStack JavaScript Software Developer, Experienced Medication Technician/CNA enthusiastic about community service and utilizing technology for the greater good.

Skills

Languages JavaScript, PostgreSQL, HTML5, CSS3, SASS Tools NodeJs, React, Express, HTTP & REST, Version Control (GIT), Unit testing, Responsive Design, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Deployment, and Hosting (Heroku, GitHub, AWS Amplify, AWS S3), Agile Operating systems:- Windows, WSL(Linux), Ubuntu

Projects

Case Hawk | October 2019 |

(https://github.com/hannaalemu/case-hawk-back-end (https://github.com/hannaalemu/case-hawk-front-end)

Web-App made to handle daily workload of small to medium-size law firms.

• JavaScript, Prisma, React-redux, and bootstrap

Project Lego | August 2019 | (https://project-lego.herokuapp.com/)

Web-App built to identify Lego Parts using the user's webcam.

- Back-End: RESTful API provides CRUD functionality on Lego Information
- Front-End: ML5 machine learning and P5 libraries used to identify Legos

Star Chaser | July 2019 | (https://starchaserdarkparks.herokuapp.com)

A mobile-first application. Dark Spot finder for those who love the stars

- Javascript, Express, NodeJS, JQuery, Responsive Design
- Google's Geocode API, DarkSky API, NASA's Image of the day API

Experience

Anaria Trading P.L.C | Front-End Developer

March 2019 - PRESENT, Addis Ababa

- Designed and developed the front-end for the company's website using Javascript, HTML, CSS, and JQuery
- Automated image optimization using minified JS and CSS, which reduced page load times by up to 30%

Maple leaf assisted Living and Memory Care | Medication Technician

July 2018 - Present, Seattle, WA

• Administered medications according to eMARs, monitored for reactions to medications, changes of condition and behavior.

Experience

Mayo Clinic | Pre-Med Insight intern

September 2017-May 2018, Rochester, MN

- Participated in workshops and skill training programs that involved shadowing doctors, medical students, and Mayo Clinic alumni.
- Mentored Apollo High school students aspiring to be healthcare professionals and provided educational and personal support.

Saint Cloud Hospital | Patient Care Assistant

January 2017-May 2018, St Cloud, MN

• Contributed as part of the patient care team in the treatment and care of patients in accordance with established policies, procedures, and unit standards to achieve the hospital's mission.

Education

Code Fellows | Seattle, WA

June 2019 - October 2019

Certificate - Advanced Software Development in Full-Stack JavaScript

Saint Cloud State University | St.Cloud, MN

August 2016 - May 2018

Nursing